- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Sorry about this barnacles,
but it's spring cleaning time.
对不起这个藤壶，
但现在是春季大扫除时间。
- I forgive you.
- 我原谅你了。
[whirring]
[呼呼]
I take it back!
[screaming]
我收回来！
[尖叫]
- There, my masterpiece.
[yelling]
- 在那里，我的杰作。
[大喊]
What the--ahh!
什么啊——啊！
- [yelling]
- [大喊]
- Ah, perfect.
- 啊，完美。
No!
[grunting]
不！
[咕噜声]
What is that menace
up to now?
那是什么威胁
到现在为止？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
How many--
[grunting]
有多少——
[咕噜声]
- Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇！哇！
- Will you please
turn that thing--
- 请你
转动那个东西——
- Oh, hey, Squidward.
- 哦，嘿，章鱼哥。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- What are you saying?
- 你在说什么？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
kids: Yay!
孩子们：耶！
- I can't hear you
over the hose noise.
- 我听不到你说话
超过软管噪音。
Hold on, I'll turn it off.
等一下，我把它关掉。
kids: Aww.
孩子们：哇。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- What's you want
to tell me, Squidward?
- 你想要什么
告诉我，章鱼哥？
- Turn off the hose.
- 关闭软管。
- I already did. Here, I'll turn
it back on just for you.
- 我已经这么做了。在这里，我要转身
它只为你而重新开启。
- No, no, no. wait--
[grunting]
- 不，不，不。等等——
[咕噜声]
- Yep, it was off.
How'd I do?
- 是的，它已经关闭了。
我怎么样？
- Horrible!
Everything you do is horrible!
- 太可怕了！
你所做的一切都太可怕了！
I wish you would
just move away already.
我希望你会
快走开吧。
- Move away?
But Squidward, I like it--
- 搬走？
但是章鱼哥，我喜欢——
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Did you see that? Huh, I
wonder what's making me sneeze.
- 你看到了吗？ Huh, I
想知道是什么让我打喷嚏。
- Ahh!
- 啊！
Probably all the barnacle dust
you kicked up.
可能全都是藤壶灰尘
你踢了起来。
- Oh, Squidward,
that makes no sense.
-哦，章鱼哥，
这毫无意义。
Who ever heard of dust
making you sneeze?
谁听说过灰尘
让你打喷嚏？
- Oh, fine, maybe you're
allergic to your pineapple.
- 哦，好吧，也许你是
对你的菠萝过敏。
- [laughing] You can't be
allergic to a house.
- [笑]你不可能
对房子过敏。
[sniffs]
[chuckles]
[嗅嗅]
[笑声]
Or could you--
no. [laughing]
或者你可以——
不。 [笑]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Oh, why do I even bother
trying to explain things to him?
哦，我为什么还要打扰
试图向他解释事情？
Of course you can be
allergic to a house.
当然你可以
对房子过敏。
I ju--wait.
我就——等等。
You can be allergic
to a house.
你可能过敏
到一所房子。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ah, ah, ah.
[stifled sneeze]
啊啊啊啊。
[打喷嚏]
[both snoring]
[两人都打呼噜]
- Ah.
[sneezes]
- 啊。
[打喷嚏]
- [growls and hisses]
- Gary, no, no, no, no!
- [咆哮和嘶嘶声]
- 加里，不，不，不，不！
- [howling]
[both grunting]
- [嚎叫]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Aww, playtime, that's nice.
- 哇哦，玩耍时间，真好。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
[horn blaring]
[喇叭声]
- [sneezes]
- [打喷嚏]
- [meows]
- Good mor--
- [喵]
- 早上好--
good mor--[sneezes]
早上好——[打喷嚏]
good--[sneezes]
好——[打喷嚏]
Good morning, Gary.
早上好，加里。
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
Ahh!
啊！
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
Ah--ah--ah--
[sneezes]
啊——啊——啊——
[打喷嚏]
Ahh!
啊！
- You okay in there, SpongeBob?
[chuckles]
- 你在里面还好吗，海绵宝宝？
[笑声]
- Oh, morning--[sneezes]
- 哦，早上好--[打喷嚏]
Morning, Squidwa--
[sneezes]
早上好，鱿鱼——
[打喷嚏]
- Oh my, having a little
sneezing fit are we?
- 天哪，有一点
我们打喷嚏适合吗？
- Yeah, I think you were right.
I must be allergic to my house.
- 是的，我认为你是对的。
我一定是对我家过敏。
- Oh, that's too bad.
I guess you'll have to move.
- 哦，那太糟糕了。
我想你得搬家了。
- Move?
- Yes. You can't stay here
- 移动？
- 是的。你不能留在这里
or your allergy
will just get worse.
或者你的过敏症
只会变得更糟。
Hey, look at that.
- Look at what?
嘿，看看那个。
- 看什么？
[sneezes]
- See?
[打喷嚏]
- 看到了吗？
Your allergy is already
getting worse.
你已经过敏了
变得更糟。
- But--but where will I go?
- Don't worry, SpongeBob.
-但是-但是我要去哪里？
- 别担心，海绵宝宝。
I'll help you find
a great new home...
我会帮你找到
一个很棒的新家...
far away from here.
离这里很远。
- But, Squidward,
I love this old pineapple.
-但是，章鱼哥，
我喜欢这个老菠萝。
We've had a lot of good times
together.
我们度过了很多美好时光
在一起。
Whee!
哎哟！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [sneezing]
- [打喷嚏]
Oh, Squidward,
my sneezing is getting worse.
哦，章鱼哥，
我的喷嚏越来越严重。
I'll miss my pineapple,
but I guess you're right.
我会想念我的菠萝
但我想你是对的。
I ha--[sneezes]
I have to move.
我哈——[打喷嚏]
我得走了。
- Now you're talking.
- 现在你在说话了。
Trust me, you'll feel
so much better
相信我，你会感觉到
好多了
when you're clear of me--
your pineapple.
当你远离我时——
你的菠萝。
- Squidward,
you're a good friend.
- 章鱼哥，
你是个好朋友。
- I know.
- 我知道。
- This would make a great new
house, what do you think?
- 这将是一个伟大的新
房子，你觉得怎么样？
- Eh.
- 呃。
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a banana
under the sea? *
*谁住在香蕉里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- Whoa!
I don't know.
- 哇！
我不知道。
- How about this spicy number?
- 这个辣数字怎么样？
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a hot pepper
under the sea? *
*谁住在辣椒里
在海底？ *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- [grunting]
所有：海绵宝宝！
- [咕哝]
- Hot listing, but no.
- 热门上市，但没有。
- Well, there's a yummy one.
- Mmm.
- 嗯，有一个很好吃的。
- 嗯。
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
Who lives in a chicken parmesan
hero under the sea?
谁住在帕尔玛鸡肉里
海底英雄？
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Nope.
没有。
- How 'bout this one?
- 这个怎么样？
- Not bad,
but let's think outside the box.
- 还不错，
但让我们跳出框框思考。
- Okay, so that's a no.
- 好吧，所以这是不。
I think I know
what you're looking for.
我想我知道
你在寻找什么。
How about this for space?
这个对于太空来说怎么样？
- Hey, what's this lever do?
- [grunts]
- 嘿，这个杠杆是做什么用的？
- [咕哝]
- Automatic balconies!
- [grunts]
- 自动阳台！
- [咕哝]
- Squidward, watch this.
- Wait, wait, no, no, no!
- 章鱼哥，看这个。
- 等等，等等，不，不，不！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Hey, Squidward, this is great.
What does this button do?
- 嘿，章鱼哥，这太棒了。
这个按钮有什么作用？
- [yelling]
- [laughing]
- [大喊]
- [笑]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- That's what it does.
- 这就是它的作用。
Aww, why couldn't I live
in that last place?
哇哦，为什么我不能活下去
在最后那个地方？
- Oh, that house was too
dangerous for you. Ow.
- 哦，那栋房子也是
对你来说很危险。噢。
Besides, it was just a house.
更何况，那只是一座房子。
But this is a castle
with a moat and everything.
但这是一座城堡
有护城河和一切。
It's a long way
from Bikini Bottom.
路还很长
来自比基尼底部。
- I know.
- Huh?
- 我知道。
- 啊？
- I mean,
don't worry about it.
- 我的意思是，
不用担心。
It's a short 11-hour commute
to the Krusty Krab from here.
通勤仅需 11 小时
从这里到蟹堡王。
- Well, I don't know,
Squidward.
- 嗯，我不知道，
章鱼哥。
It doesn't seem like
the safest neighborhood.
看起来不像
最安全的社区。
- All right, SpongeBob, this is
the last house on my list,
- 好吧，海绵宝宝，这是
我名单上的最后一所房子
but I think it's got everything
you're looking for.
但我认为它拥有一切
你正在寻找。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
- I don't know.
It doesn't look like much.
- 我不知道。
看起来并不多。
both: Wow.
两人：哇。
- Pretty!
- 漂亮的！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
This place is amazing.
这个地方太棒了。
It's like living
in the future.
这就像生活
在未来。
- Ooh, check out
these cool stairs.
- 哦，看看
这些很酷的楼梯。
Whee!
哎哟！
- Uh, SpongeBob?
- Whee!
- 呃，海绵宝宝？
- 呼！
- [grunting]
- Squidward? Squidward?
- [咕哝]
- 章鱼哥？章鱼哥？
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- This place is awesome.
- 这个地方太棒了。
[back cracking]
- Yeah, it is, isn't it?
[背部开裂]
- 是的，是的，不是吗？
I can't believe
I get to live here.
我不敢相信
我可以住在这里。
It's so much cooler
than your house.
凉快多了
比你的房子。
- [grunting]
You're right.
- [咕哝]
你是对的。
This place is way too cool
for you.
这个地方太酷了
为了你。
- Wait, what?
- I mean, living in a place
- 等等，什么？
- 我的意思是，住在一个地方
like this can put
a lot of pressure on a guy.
像这样可以放
对一个人来说压力很大。
The constant attention
you get,
持续的关注
你得到，
and all the fabulous parties
you'd host.
以及所有精彩的派对
你会主持。
[playing flute]
[长笛演奏]
Eh?
- Oh, it's quite good.
呃？
- 哦，这很好。
- Certainly worthy
of this house.
- 当然值得
这所房子的。
- [whimpering]
- Indeed.
- [呜咽]
- 确实如此。
- Not to mention
all the covers
- 更不用说
所有封面
of "Cool Calamari"
you'd have to pose for.
《酷鱿鱼》
你必须摆出姿势。
No, I can't let you
go through that, SpongeBob.
不，我不能让你
海绵宝宝，经历一下吧。
So I tell you what,
I'll live here for you.
所以我告诉你什么，
我会为你住在这里。
- Yeah, but where will I live?
- You can have my old house.
- 是的，但是我住在哪里？
- 你可以拥有我的老房子。
- Really?
That is so nice of you.
- 真的吗？
你真是太好了。
That way I'll be one house
closer to Patrick.
这样我就成为一所房子
离帕特里克更近了。
- Great, it's a done deal.
- 太好了，事情就这么定了。
So if you don't mind, I have
a lot of settling in to do.
所以如果你不介意的话，我有
有很多事情要做。
Bye-bye.
- Okay, so I guess
再见。
- 好吧，所以我猜
I'll see you la--
我会见到你拉--
- [sighs] Now this is how
I was always meant to live.
- [叹气]现在就是这样
我本来就注定要活下去。
[chuckles and yawns]
[轻笑和哈欠]
Bedtime.
就寝时间。
Oh, a built in alarm clock.
Hoo, this place has got it all.
哦，内置闹钟。
呼，这个地方已经拥有了一切。
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[horns blaring]
- Ten, nine, eight...
[喇叭声]
- 十、九、八……
Wha--what's happening?
- Seven, six, five...
什——发生什么事了？
- 七、六、五……
- Oh, no.
It's not an alarm clock.
- 哦，不。
这不是闹钟。
It's a countdown!
- Four, three, two, one.
这是倒计时！
- 四，三，二，一。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Huh? What--what the--
uh.
啊？什么——什么——
呃。
That was horrible.
那太可怕了。
But this is even worse!
但这更糟糕！
Ahh!
啊！
- Doink.
Now this really feels like home.
- 多因克。
现在这里真的感觉像家一样。
Ahh!
啊！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Squidward, you dropped in
for a visit.
- 章鱼哥，你进来了
参观。
- I am not visiting.
- 我不来拜访。
This is my house
and I want it back.
这是我的房子
我想要它回来。
- Sorry, Squidward, but you gave
it to me fair and square...
- 对不起，章鱼哥，但你给了
对我来说公平公正...
pants.
裤子。
Besides, if I move out now,
I have no where to go.
另外，如果我现在搬出去，
我无处可去。
- Okay, fine, I'll just take
your old pineapple.
- 好吧，好吧，我就接受
你的老菠萝
Huh?
啊？
- Sorry, Squidward,
but this is my house now.
- 对不起，章鱼哥，
但这现在是我的房子了。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
- Well, then, where am I
supposed to live?
- 那么，我在哪里
应该活着吗？
- Night, Squidward.
- [grumbles]
- 晚安，章鱼哥。
- [抱怨]
[sneezes]
Ow.
[打喷嚏]
噢。